<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Ask Dav</title><link>http://askdav.com/</link><description>Movement. Science. Climate. Data.</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:05:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Practicing Inhibition and Selection</title><link>http://askdav.com/posts/practicing-inhibition-and-selection.html</link><dc:creator>@davclark</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://askdav.com/donut.svg" style="width: 200px; max-width: 100%; height: auto; float: right" alt="A perception, a thought, an action..."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking an interest in the materials I presented at ISCS 2014. I’m
excited to collaborate with you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be producing a recorded intervention in the coming week or so, but I still
need to square things aware with our IRB! In the meantime, please sign up on
&lt;a href="https://osf.io/btc5f/"&gt;the Open Science Framework (OSF) project&lt;/a&gt;, or just email
me at davclark@berkeley.edu to be kept in the loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://askdav.com/posts/practicing-inhibition-and-selection.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>talk</category><guid>http://askdav.com/posts/practicing-inhibition-and-selection.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Empowering Victims</title><link>http://askdav.com/posts/empowering-victims.html</link><dc:creator>@davclark</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early 70’s, Steve Paxton’s embarked on an series of experiments with
physicality that he said was missing from dance at the time. He was inspired in
particular by the martial arts. Steve submitted a grant proposal to the NEA, who
proceeded to fund these experiments – initially a small group of athletic men
literally throwing themselves at each other to see what could happen. If you
manage to see some footage of these first experiments, it looks pretty nuts, and
it was – the first participants couldn’t keep up this level of intensity, and
they toned things down rapidly after the first couple of weeks! &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9FeSDsmIeHA#t=2m42s"&gt;This
video&lt;/a&gt; shows some of the
preparation for their first performance. You can see there that women had
already been included, and – while it may be much harder to see – there’s a
clear focus on safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From those initial experiments, Contact Improv has become a true folk art, and
it’s now under continuing development (somewhat anarchically) by the community
that practices it.  There is no appreciable culture of critics, and no real
audience to speak of (though some claim it is the “largest” influence on where
contemporary dance has gone in recent times). One particular point of contention
is embodied by Steve Paxton’s assertion that “If you’re dancing physics, you’re
dancing contact. if you’re dancing chemistry, you’re doing something else.” But
this debate is an aspirational one at best – any interaction between two human
bodies will involve both physics and the emotional stuff that comes up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://askdav.com/posts/empowering-victims.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>dance</category><category>equity</category><guid>http://askdav.com/posts/empowering-victims.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 03:16:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>About This Site</title><link>http://askdav.com/posts/about-this-site.html</link><dc:creator>@davclark</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What’s this about?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is largely my own “kicking the tires” on
&lt;a href="http://getnikola.com"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt;. The important information from this post should
make its way to an about page or a sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently work in the &lt;a href="http://dlab.berkeley.edu"&gt;D-Lab&lt;/a&gt;, with a strong focus
on public-facing science. Notably, I’m working with &lt;a href="http://oroeco.com"&gt;Oroeco&lt;/a&gt;
and others on climate and behavior, and generally interested in science with
social impacts, currently focused on &lt;a href="http://statsforchange.com"&gt;Stats for
Change&lt;/a&gt; (a Bay Area hub) and the &lt;a href="http://dssg.io"&gt;Data Science for
Social Good Fellows Program&lt;/a&gt;. I’m also interested in the role of
personal development, ranging from education to “mindful practice” (like
meditation, taiji, the Feldenkrais Method®, and Contact Improv).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design of this site is meant to support &amp;amp; cross-reference that work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://askdav.com/posts/about-this-site.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>about</category><guid>http://askdav.com/posts/about-this-site.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 06:06:08 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>